<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<rss xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>OpenClaw</title>
        <item>
            <title>2026.3.1</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2026 04:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>2026030190</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.3.1</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.3.1</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Agents/Thinking defaults: set <code>adaptive</code> as the default thinking level for Anthropic Claude 4.6 models (including Bedrock Claude 4.6 refs) while keeping other reasoning-capable models at <code>low</code> unless explicitly configured.</li>
<li>Gateway/Container probes: add built-in HTTP liveness/readiness endpoints (<code>/health</code>, <code>/healthz</code>, <code>/ready</code>, <code>/readyz</code>) for Docker/Kubernetes health checks, with fallback routing so existing handlers on those paths are not shadowed. (#31272) Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Android/Nodes: add <code>camera.list</code>, <code>device.permissions</code>, <code>device.health</code>, and <code>notifications.actions</code> (<code>open</code>/<code>dismiss</code>/<code>reply</code>) on Android nodes, plus first-class node-tool actions for the new device/notification commands. (#28260) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Discord/Thread bindings: replace fixed TTL lifecycle with inactivity (<code>idleHours</code>, default 24h) plus optional hard <code>maxAgeHours</code> lifecycle controls, and add <code>/session idle</code> + <code>/session max-age</code> commands for focused thread-bound sessions. (#27845) Thanks @osolmaz.</li>
<li>Telegram/DM topics: add per-DM <code>direct</code> + topic config (allowlists, <code>dmPolicy</code>, <code>skills</code>, <code>systemPrompt</code>, <code>requireTopic</code>), route DM topics as distinct inbound/outbound sessions, and enforce topic-aware authorization/debounce for messages, callbacks, commands, and reactions. Landed from contributor PR #30579 by @kesor. Thanks @kesor.</li>
<li>Web UI/Cron i18n: localize cron page labels, filters, form help text, and validation/error messaging in English and zh-CN. (#29315) Thanks @BUGKillerKing.</li>
<li>OpenAI/Streaming transport: make <code>openai</code> Responses WebSocket-first by default (<code>transport: "auto"</code> with SSE fallback), add shared OpenAI WS stream/connection runtime wiring with per-session cleanup, and preserve server-side compaction payload mutation (<code>store</code> + <code>context_management</code>) on the WS path.</li>
<li>Android/Gateway capability refresh: add live Android capability integration coverage and node canvas capability refresh wiring, plus runtime hardening for A2UI readiness retries, scoped canvas URL normalization, debug diagnostics JSON, and JavaScript MIME delivery. (#28388) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Android/Nodes parity: add <code>system.notify</code>, <code>photos.latest</code>, <code>contacts.search</code>/<code>contacts.add</code>, <code>calendar.events</code>/<code>calendar.add</code>, and <code>motion.activity</code>/<code>motion.pedometer</code>, with motion sensor-aware command gating and improved activity sampling reliability. (#29398) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>CLI/Config: add <code>openclaw config file</code> to print the active config file path resolved from <code>OPENCLAW_CONFIG_PATH</code> or the default location. (#26256) thanks @cyb1278588254.</li>
<li>Feishu/Docx tables + uploads: add <code>feishu_doc</code> actions for Docx table creation/cell writing (<code>create_table</code>, <code>write_table_cells</code>, <code>create_table_with_values</code>) and image/file uploads (<code>upload_image</code>, <code>upload_file</code>) with stricter create/upload error handling for missing <code>document_id</code> and placeholder cleanup failures. (#20304) Thanks @xuhao1.</li>
<li>Feishu/Reactions: add inbound <code>im.message.reaction.created_v1</code> handling, route verified reactions through synthetic inbound turns, and harden verification with timeout + fail-closed filtering so non-bot or unverified reactions are dropped. (#16716) Thanks @schumilin.</li>
<li>Feishu/Chat tooling: add <code>feishu_chat</code> tool actions for chat info and member queries, with configurable enablement under <code>channels.feishu.tools.chat</code>. (#14674) Thanks @liuweifly.</li>
<li>Feishu/Doc permissions: support optional owner permission grant fields on <code>feishu_doc</code> create and report permission metadata only when the grant call succeeds, with regression coverage for success/failure/omitted-owner paths. (#28295) Thanks @zhoulongchao77.</li>
<li>Web UI/i18n: add German (<code>de</code>) locale support and auto-render language options from supported locale constants in Overview settings. (#28495) thanks @dsantoreis.</li>
<li>Tools/Diffs: add a new optional <code>diffs</code> plugin tool for read-only diff rendering from before/after text or unified patches, with gateway viewer URLs for canvas and PNG image output. Thanks @gumadeiras.</li>
<li>Memory/LanceDB: support custom OpenAI <code>baseUrl</code> and embedding dimensions for LanceDB memory. (#17874) Thanks @rish2jain and @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>ACP/ACPX streaming: pin ACPX plugin support to <code>0.1.15</code>, add configurable ACPX command/version probing, and streamline ACP stream delivery (<code>final_only</code> default + reduced tool-event noise) with matching runtime and test updates. (#30036) Thanks @osolmaz.</li>
<li>Shell env markers: set <code>OPENCLAW_SHELL</code> across shell-like runtimes (<code>exec</code>, <code>acp</code>, <code>acp-client</code>, <code>tui-local</code>) so shell startup/config rules can target OpenClaw contexts consistently, and document the markers in env/exec/acp/TUI docs. Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Cron/Heartbeat light bootstrap context: add opt-in lightweight bootstrap mode for automation runs (<code>--light-context</code> for cron agent turns and <code>agents.*.heartbeat.lightContext</code> for heartbeat), keeping only <code>HEARTBEAT.md</code> for heartbeat runs and skipping bootstrap-file injection for cron lightweight runs. (#26064) Thanks @jose-velez.</li>
<li>OpenAI/WebSocket warm-up: add optional OpenAI Responses WebSocket warm-up (<code>response.create</code> with <code>generate:false</code>), enable it by default for <code>openai/*</code>, and expose <code>params.openaiWsWarmup</code> for per-model enable/disable control.</li>
<li>Agents/Subagents runtime events: replace ad-hoc subagent completion system-message handoff with typed internal completion events (<code>task_completion</code>) that are rendered consistently across direct and queued announce paths, with gateway/CLI plumbing for structured <code>internalEvents</code>.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Breaking</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>BREAKING:</strong> Node exec approval payloads now require <code>systemRunPlan</code>. <code>host=node</code> approval requests without that plan are rejected.</li>
<li><strong>BREAKING:</strong> Node <code>system.run</code> execution now pins path-token commands to the canonical executable path (<code>realpath</code>) in both allowlist and approval execution flows. Integrations/tests that asserted token-form argv (for example <code>tr</code>) must now accept canonical paths (for example <code>/usr/bin/tr</code>).</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Android/Nodes reliability: reject <code>facing=both</code> when <code>deviceId</code> is set to avoid mislabeled duplicate captures, allow notification <code>open</code>/<code>reply</code> on non-clearable entries while still gating dismiss, trigger listener rebind before notification actions, and scale invoke-result ack timeout to invoke budget for large clip payloads. (#28260) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Windows/Plugin install: avoid <code>spawn EINVAL</code> on Windows npm/npx invocations by resolving to <code>node</code> + npm CLI scripts instead of spawning <code>.cmd</code> directly. Landed from contributor PR #31147 by @codertony. Thanks @codertony.</li>
<li>LINE/Voice transcription: classify M4A voice media as <code>audio/mp4</code> (not <code>video/mp4</code>) by checking the MPEG-4 <code>ftyp</code> major brand (<code>M4A </code> / <code>M4B </code>), restoring voice transcription for LINE voice messages. Landed from contributor PR #31151 by @scoootscooob. Thanks @scoootscooob.</li>
<li>Slack/Announce target account routing: enable session-backed announce-target lookup for Slack so multi-account announces resolve the correct <code>accountId</code> instead of defaulting to bot-token context. Landed from contributor PR #31028 by @taw0002. Thanks @taw0002.</li>
<li>Android/Voice screen TTS: stream assistant speech via ElevenLabs WebSocket in Talk Mode, stop cleanly on speaker mute/barge-in, and ignore stale out-of-order stream events. (#29521) Thanks @gregmousseau.</li>
<li>Android/Photos permissions: declare Android 14+ selected-photo access permission (<code>READ_MEDIA_VISUAL_USER_SELECTED</code>) and align Android permission/settings paths with current minSdk behavior for more reliable permission state handling.</li>
<li>Web UI/Cron: include configured agent model defaults/fallbacks in cron model suggestions so scheduled-job model autocomplete reflects configured models. (#29709) Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Cron/Delivery: disable the agent messaging tool when <code>delivery.mode</code> is <code>"none"</code> so cron output is not sent to Telegram or other channels. (#21808) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>CLI/Cron: clarify <code>cron list</code> output by renaming <code>Agent</code> to <code>Agent ID</code> and adding a <code>Model</code> column for isolated agent-turn jobs. (#26259) Thanks @openperf.</li>
<li>Feishu/Reply media attachments: send Feishu reply <code>mediaUrl</code>/<code>mediaUrls</code> payloads as attachments alongside text/streamed replies in the reply dispatcher, including legacy fallback when <code>mediaUrls</code> is empty. (#28959) Thanks @icesword0760.</li>
<li>Slack/User-token resolution: normalize Slack account user-token sourcing through resolved account metadata (<code>SLACK_USER_TOKEN</code> env + config) so monitor reads, Slack actions, directory lookups, onboarding allow-from resolution, and capabilities probing consistently use the effective user token. (#28103) Thanks @Glucksberg.</li>
<li>Feishu/Outbound session routing: stop assuming bare <code>oc_</code> identifiers are always group chats, honor explicit <code>dm:</code>/<code>group:</code> prefixes for <code>oc_</code> chat IDs, and default ambiguous bare <code>oc_</code> targets to direct routing to avoid DM session misclassification. (#10407) Thanks @Bermudarat.</li>
<li>Feishu/Group session routing: add configurable group session scopes (<code>group</code>, <code>group_sender</code>, <code>group_topic</code>, <code>group_topic_sender</code>) with legacy <code>topicSessionMode=enabled</code> compatibility so Feishu group conversations can isolate sessions by sender/topic as configured. (#17798) Thanks @yfge.</li>
<li>Feishu/Reply-in-thread routing: add <code>replyInThread</code> config (<code>disabled|enabled</code>) for group replies, propagate <code>reply_in_thread</code> across text/card/media/streaming sends, and align topic-scoped session routing so newly created reply threads stay on the same session root. (#27325) Thanks @kcinzgg.</li>
<li>Feishu/Probe status caching: cache successful <code>probeFeishu()</code> bot-info results for 10 minutes (bounded cache with per-account keying) to reduce repeated status/onboarding probe API calls, while bypassing cache for failures and exceptions. (#28907) Thanks @Glucksberg.</li>
<li>Feishu/Opus media send type: send <code>.opus</code> attachments with <code>msg_type: "audio"</code> (instead of <code>"media"</code>) so Feishu voice messages deliver correctly while <code>.mp4</code> remains <code>msg_type: "media"</code> and documents remain <code>msg_type: "file"</code>. (#28269) Thanks @Glucksberg.</li>
<li>Feishu/Mobile video media type: treat inbound <code>message_type: "media"</code> as video-equivalent for media key extraction, placeholder inference, and media download resolution so mobile-app video sends ingest correctly. (#25502) Thanks @4ier.</li>
<li>Feishu/Inbound sender fallback: fall back to <code>sender_id.user_id</code> when <code>sender_id.open_id</code> is missing on inbound events, and use ID-type-aware sender lookup so mobile-delivered messages keep stable sender identity/routing. (#26703) Thanks @NewdlDewdl.</li>
<li>Feishu/Reply context metadata: include inbound <code>parent_id</code> and <code>root_id</code> as <code>ReplyToId</code>/<code>RootMessageId</code> in inbound context, and parse interactive-card quote bodies into readable text when fetching replied messages. (#18529) Thanks @qiangu.</li>
<li>Feishu/Post embedded media: extract <code>media</code> tags from inbound rich-text (<code>post</code>) messages and download embedded video/audio files alongside existing embedded-image handling, with regression coverage. (#21786) Thanks @laopuhuluwa.</li>
<li>Feishu/Local media sends: propagate <code>mediaLocalRoots</code> through Feishu outbound media sending into <code>loadWebMedia</code> so local path attachments work with post-CVE local-root enforcement. (#27884) Thanks @joelnishanth.</li>
<li>Feishu/Group wildcard policy fallback: honor <code>channels.feishu.groups["*"]</code> when no explicit group match exists so unmatched groups inherit wildcard reply-policy settings instead of falling back to global defaults. (#29456) Thanks @WaynePika.</li>
<li>Feishu/Inbound media regression coverage: add explicit tests for message resource type mapping (<code>image</code> stays <code>image</code>, non-image maps to <code>file</code>) to prevent reintroducing unsupported Feishu <code>type=audio</code> fetches. (#16311, #8746) Thanks @Yaxuan42.</li>
<li>TTS/Voice bubbles: use opus output and enable <code>audioAsVoice</code> routing for Feishu and WhatsApp (in addition to Telegram) so supported channels receive voice-bubble playback instead of file-style audio attachments. (#27366) Thanks @smthfoxy.</li>
<li>Telegram/Reply media context: include replied media files in inbound context when replying to media, defer reply-media downloads to debounce flush, gate reply-media fetch behind DM authorization, and preserve replied media when non-vision sticker fallback runs (including cached-sticker paths). (#28488) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Android/Nodes notification wake flow: enable Android <code>system.notify</code> default allowlist, emit <code>notifications.changed</code> events for posted/removed notifications (excluding OpenClaw app-owned notifications), canonicalize notification session keys before enqueue/wake routing, and skip heartbeat wakes when consecutive notification summaries dedupe. (#29440) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Telegram/Voice fallback reply chunking: apply reply reference, quote text, and inline buttons only to the first fallback text chunk when voice delivery is blocked, preventing over-quoted multi-chunk replies. Landed from contributor PR #31067 by @xdanger. Thanks @xdanger.</li>
<li>Feishu/Multi-account + reply reliability: add <code>channels.feishu.defaultAccount</code> outbound routing support with schema validation, keep quoted-message extraction text-first (post/interactive/file placeholders instead of raw JSON), route Feishu video sends as <code>msg_type: "file"</code>, and avoid websocket event blocking by using non-blocking event handling in monitor dispatch. Landed from contributor PRs #29610, #30432, #30331, and #29501. Thanks @hclsys, @bmendonca3, @patrick-yingxi-pan, and @zwffff.</li>
<li>Cron/Delivery: disable the agent messaging tool when <code>delivery.mode</code> is <code>"none"</code> so cron output is not sent to Telegram or other channels. (#21808) Thanks @lailoo.</li>
<li>Feishu/Inbound rich-text parsing: preserve <code>share_chat</code> payload summaries when available and add explicit parsing for rich-text <code>code</code>/<code>code_block</code>/<code>pre</code> tags so forwarded and code-heavy messages keep useful context in agent input. (#28591) Thanks @kevinWangSheng.</li>
<li>Feishu/Post markdown parsing: parse rich-text <code>post</code> payloads through a shared markdown-aware parser with locale-wrapper support, preserved mention/image metadata extraction, and inline/fenced code fidelity for agent input rendering. (#12755) Thanks @WilsonLiu95.</li>
<li>Telegram/Outbound chunking: route oversize splitting through the shared outbound pipeline (including subagents), retry Telegram sends when escaped HTML exceeds limits, and preserve boundary whitespace when retry re-splitting rendered chunks so plain-text/transcript fidelity is retained. (#29342, #27317; follow-up to #27461) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Slack/Native commands: register Slack native status as <code>/agentstatus</code> (Slack-reserved <code>/status</code>) so manifest slash command registration stays valid while text <code>/status</code> still works. Landed from contributor PR #29032 by @maloqab. Thanks @maloqab.</li>
<li>Android/Camera clip: remove <code>camera.clip</code> HTTP-upload fallback to base64 so clip transport is deterministic and fail-loud, and reject non-positive <code>maxWidth</code> values so invalid inputs fall back to the safe resize default. (#28229) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Android/Gateway canvas capability refresh: send <code>node.canvas.capability.refresh</code> with object <code>params</code> (<code>{}</code>) from Android node runtime so gateway object-schema validation accepts refresh retries and A2UI host recovery works after scoped capability expiry. (#28413) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Gateway/Control UI origins: honor <code>gateway.controlUi.allowedOrigins: ["*"]</code> wildcard entries (including trimmed values) and lock behavior with regression tests. Landed from contributor PR #31058 by @byungsker. Thanks @byungsker.</li>
<li>Web UI/Cron: include configured agent model defaults/fallbacks in cron model suggestions so scheduled-job model autocomplete reflects configured models. (#29709) Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Agents/Sessions list transcript paths: handle missing/non-string/relative <code>sessions.list.path</code> values and per-agent <code>{agentId}</code> templates when deriving <code>transcriptPath</code>, so cross-agent session listings resolve to concrete agent session files instead of workspace-relative paths. (#24775) Thanks @martinfrancois.</li>
<li>Gateway/Control UI CSP: allow required Google Fonts origins in Control UI CSP. (#29279) Thanks @Glucksberg and @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>CLI/Install: add an npm-link fallback to fix CLI startup <code>Permission denied</code> failures (<code>exit 127</code>) on affected installs. (#17151) Thanks @sskyu and @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Onboarding/Custom providers: improve verification reliability for slower local endpoints (for example Ollama) during setup. (#27380) Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Plugins/NPM spec install: fix npm-spec plugin installs when <code>npm pack</code> output is empty by detecting newly created <code>.tgz</code> archives in the pack directory. (#21039) Thanks @graysurf and @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Plugins/Install: clear stale install errors when an npm package is not found so follow-up install attempts report current state correctly. (#25073) Thanks @dalefrieswthat.</li>
<li>Security/Feishu webhook ingress: bound unauthenticated webhook rate-limit state with stale-window pruning and a hard key cap to prevent unbounded pre-auth memory growth from rotating source keys. (#26050) Thanks @bmendonca3.</li>
<li>Gateway/macOS supervised restart: actively <code>launchctl kickstart -k</code> during intentional supervised restarts to bypass LaunchAgent <code>ThrottleInterval</code> delays, and fall back to in-process restart when kickstart fails. Landed from contributor PR #29078 by @cathrynlavery. Thanks @cathrynlavery.</li>
<li>Daemon/macOS TLS certs: default LaunchAgent service env <code>NODE_EXTRA_CA_CERTS</code> to <code>/etc/ssl/cert.pem</code> (while preserving explicit overrides) so HTTPS clients no longer fail with local-issuer errors under launchd. (#27915) Thanks @Lukavyi.</li>
<li>Discord/Components wildcard handlers: use distinct internal registration sentinel IDs and parse those sentinels as wildcard keys so select/user/role/channel/mentionable/modal interactions are not dropped by raw customId dedupe paths. Landed from contributor PR #29459 by @Sid-Qin. Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Feishu/Reaction notifications: add <code>channels.feishu.reactionNotifications</code> (<code>off | own | all</code>, default <code>own</code>) so operators can disable reaction ingress or allow all verified reaction events (not only bot-authored message reactions). (#28529) Thanks @cowboy129.</li>
<li>Feishu/Typing backoff: re-throw Feishu typing add/remove rate-limit and quota errors (<code>429</code>, <code>99991400</code>, <code>99991403</code>) and detect SDK non-throwing backoff responses so the typing keepalive circuit breaker can stop retries instead of looping indefinitely. (#28494) Thanks @guoqunabc.</li>
<li>Feishu/Zalo runtime logging: replace direct <code>console.log/error</code> usage in Feishu typing-indicator paths and Zalo monitor paths with runtime-gated logger calls so verbosity controls are respected while preserving typing backoff behavior. (#18841) Thanks @Clawborn.</li>
<li>Feishu/Group sender allowlist fallback: add global <code>channels.feishu.groupSenderAllowFrom</code> sender authorization for group chats, with per-group <code>groups.<id>.allowFrom</code> precedence and regression coverage for allow/block/precedence behavior. (#29174) Thanks @1MoreBuild.</li>
<li>Feishu/Docx append/write ordering: insert converted Docx blocks sequentially (single-block creates) so Feishu append/write preserves markdown block order instead of returning shuffled sections in asynchronous batch inserts. (#26172, #26022) Thanks @echoVic.</li>
<li>Feishu/Docx convert fallback chunking: recursively split oversized markdown chunks (including long no-heading sections) when <code>document.convert</code> hits content limits, while keeping fenced-code-aware split boundaries whenever possible. (#14402) Thanks @lml2468.</li>
<li>Feishu/API quota controls: add <code>typingIndicator</code> and <code>resolveSenderNames</code> config flags (top-level and per-account) so operators can disable typing reactions and sender-name lookup requests while keeping default behavior unchanged. (#10513) Thanks @BigUncle.</li>
<li>Feishu/System preview prompt leakage: stop enqueuing inbound Feishu message previews as system events so user preview text is not injected into later turns as trusted <code>System:</code> context. Landed from contributor PR #31209 by @stakeswky. Thanks @stakeswky.</li>
<li>Feishu/Typing replay suppression: skip typing indicators for stale replayed inbound messages after compaction using message-age checks with second/millisecond timestamp normalization, preventing old-message reaction floods while preserving typing for fresh messages. Landed from contributor PR #30709 by @arkyu2077. Thanks @arkyu2077.</li>
<li>Sessions/Internal routing: preserve established external <code>lastTo</code>/<code>lastChannel</code> routes for internal/non-deliverable turns, with added coverage for no-fallback internal routing behavior. Landed from contributor PR #30941 by @graysurf. Thanks @graysurf.</li>
<li>Control UI/Debug log layout: render Debug Event Log payloads at full width to prevent payload JSON from being squeezed into a narrow side column. Landed from contributor PR #30978 by @stozo04. Thanks @stozo04.</li>
<li>Auto-reply/NO_REPLY: strip <code>NO_REPLY</code> token from mixed-content messages instead of leaking raw control text to end users. Landed from contributor PR #31080 by @scoootscooob. Thanks @scoootscooob.</li>
<li>Install/npm: fix npm global install deprecation warnings. (#28318) Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Update/Global npm: fallback to <code>--omit=optional</code> when global <code>npm update</code> fails so optional dependency install failures no longer abort update flows. (#24896) Thanks @xinhuagu and @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Inbound metadata/Multi-account routing: include <code>account_id</code> in trusted inbound metadata so multi-account channel sessions can reliably disambiguate the receiving account in prompt context. Landed from contributor PR #30984 by @Stxle2. Thanks @Stxle2.</li>
<li>Model directives/Auth profiles: split <code>/model</code> profile suffixes at the first <code>@</code> after the last slash so email-based auth profile IDs (for example OAuth profile IDs) resolve correctly. Landed from contributor PR #30932 by @haosenwang1018. Thanks @haosenwang1018.</li>
<li>Cron/Delivery mode none: send explicit <code>delivery: { mode: "none" }</code> from cron editor for both add and update flows so previous announce delivery is actually cleared. Landed from contributor PR #31145 by @byungsker. Thanks @byungsker.</li>
<li>Cron editor viewport: make the sticky cron edit form independently scrollable with viewport-bounded height so lower fields/actions are reachable on shorter screens. Landed from contributor PR #31133 by @Sid-Qin. Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Agents/Thinking fallback: when providers reject unsupported thinking levels without enumerating alternatives, retry with <code>think=off</code> to avoid hard failure during model/provider fallback chains. Landed from contributor PR #31002 by @yfge. Thanks @yfge.</li>
<li>Ollama/Embedded runner base URL precedence: prioritize configured provider <code>baseUrl</code> over model defaults for embedded Ollama runs so Docker and remote-host setups avoid localhost fetch failures. (#30964) Thanks @stakeswky.</li>
<li>Agents/Failover reason classification: avoid false rate-limit classification from incidental <code>tpm</code> substrings by matching TPM as a standalone token/phrase and keeping auth-context errors on the auth path. Landed from contributor PR #31007 by @HOYALIM. Thanks @HOYALIM.</li>
<li>CLI/Cron: clarify <code>cron list</code> output by renaming <code>Agent</code> to <code>Agent ID</code> and adding a <code>Model</code> column for isolated agent-turn jobs. (#26259) Thanks @openperf.</li>
<li>Gateway/WS: close repeated post-handshake <code>unauthorized role:*</code> request floods per connection and sample duplicate rejection logs, preventing a single misbehaving client from degrading gateway responsiveness. (#20168) Thanks @acy103, @vibecodooor, and @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Gateway/Auth: improve device-auth v2 migration diagnostics so operators get clearer guidance when legacy clients connect. (#28305) Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>CLI/Ollama config: allow <code>config set</code> for Ollama <code>apiKey</code> without predeclared provider config. (#29299) Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Ollama/Autodiscovery: harden autodiscovery and warning behavior. (#29201) Thanks @marcodelpin and @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Ollama/Context window: unify context window handling across discovery, merge, and OpenAI-compatible transport paths. (#29205) Thanks @Sid-Qin, @jimmielightner, and @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Agents/Ollama: demote empty-discovery logging from <code>warn</code> to <code>debug</code> to reduce noisy warnings in normal edge-case discovery flows. (#26379) Thanks @byungsker.</li>
<li>fix(model): preserve reasoning in provider fallback resolution. (#29285) Fixes #25636. Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Docker/Image permissions: normalize <code>/app/extensions</code>, <code>/app/.agent</code>, and <code>/app/.agents</code> to directory mode <code>755</code> and file mode <code>644</code> during image build so plugin discovery does not block inherited world-writable paths. (#30191) Fixes #30139. Thanks @edincampara.</li>
<li>OpenAI Responses/Compaction: rewrite and unify the OpenAI Responses store patches to treat empty <code>baseUrl</code> as non-direct, honor <code>compat.supportsStore=false</code>, and auto-inject server-side compaction <code>context_management</code> for compatible direct OpenAI models (with per-model opt-out/threshold overrides). Landed from contributor PRs #16930 (@OiPunk), #22441 (@EdwardWu7), and #25088 (@MoerAI). Thanks @OiPunk, @EdwardWu7, and @MoerAI.</li>
<li>Sandbox/Browser Docker: pass <code>OPENCLAW_BROWSER_NO_SANDBOX=1</code> to sandbox browser containers and bump sandbox browser security hash epoch so existing containers are recreated and pick up the env on upgrade. (#29879) Thanks @Lukavyi.</li>
<li>Usage normalization: clamp negative prompt/input token values to zero (including <code>prompt_tokens</code> alias inputs) so <code>/usage</code> and TUI usage displays cannot show nonsensical negative counts. Landed from contributor PR #31211 by @scoootscooob. Thanks @scoootscooob.</li>
<li>Secrets/Auth profiles: normalize inline SecretRef <code>token</code>/<code>key</code> values to canonical <code>tokenRef</code>/<code>keyRef</code> before persistence, and keep explicit <code>keyRef</code> precedence when inline refs are also present. Landed from contributor PR #31047 by @minupla. Thanks @minupla.</li>
<li>Tools/Edit workspace boundary errors: preserve the real <code>Path escapes workspace root</code> failure path instead of surfacing a misleading access/file-not-found error when editing outside workspace roots. Landed from contributor PR #31015 by @haosenwang1018. Thanks @haosenwang1018.</li>
<li>Browser/Open & navigate: accept <code>url</code> as an alias parameter for <code>open</code> and <code>navigate</code>. (#29260) Thanks @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Codex/Usage window: label weekly usage window as <code>Week</code> instead of <code>Day</code>. (#26267) Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Signal/Sync message null-handling: treat <code>syncMessage</code> presence (including <code>null</code>) as sync envelope traffic so replayed sentTranscript payloads cannot bypass loop guards after daemon restart. Landed from contributor PR #31138 by @Sid-Qin. Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Infra/fs-safe: sanitize directory-read failures so raw <code>EISDIR</code> text never leaks to messaging surfaces, with regression tests for both root-scoped and direct safe reads. Landed from contributor PR #31205 by @polooooo. Thanks @polooooo.</li>
<li>Sandbox/mkdirp boundary checks: allow directory-safe boundary validation for existing in-boundary subdirectories, preventing false <code>cannot create directories</code> failures in sandbox write mode. (#30610) Thanks @glitch418x.</li>
<li>Security/Compaction audit: remove the post-compaction audit injection message. (#28507) Thanks @fuller-stack-dev and @vincentkoc.</li>
<li>Web tools/RFC2544 fake-IP compatibility: allow RFC2544 benchmark range (<code>198.18.0.0/15</code>) for trusted web-tool fetch endpoints so proxy fake-IP networking modes do not trigger false SSRF blocks. Landed from contributor PR #31176 by @sunkinux. Thanks @sunkinux.</li>
<li>Telegram/Voice fallback reply chunking: apply reply reference, quote text, and inline buttons only to the first fallback text chunk when voice delivery is blocked, preventing over-quoted multi-chunk replies. Landed from contributor PR #31067 by @xdanger. Thanks @xdanger.</li>
<li>Feishu/System preview prompt leakage: stop enqueuing inbound Feishu message previews as system events so user preview text is not injected into later turns as trusted <code>System:</code> context. Landed from contributor PR #31209 by @stakeswky. Thanks @stakeswky.</li>
<li>Feishu/Multi-account + reply reliability: add <code>channels.feishu.defaultAccount</code> outbound routing support with schema validation, keep quoted-message extraction text-first (post/interactive/file placeholders instead of raw JSON), route Feishu video sends as <code>msg_type: "file"</code>, and avoid websocket event blocking by using non-blocking event handling in monitor dispatch. Landed from contributor PRs #29610, #30432, #30331, and #29501. Thanks @hclsys, @bmendonca3, @patrick-yingxi-pan, and @zwffff.</li>
<li>Feishu/Typing replay suppression: skip typing indicators for stale replayed inbound messages after compaction using message-age checks with second/millisecond timestamp normalization, preventing old-message reaction floods while preserving typing for fresh messages. Landed from contributor PR #30709 by @arkyu2077. Thanks @arkyu2077.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.3.1/OpenClaw-2026.3.1.zip" length="12804155" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="TF1otD4Vk3pG0iViX7mvix5DQEgAsk4JkSFvH7opjf9aawV16f29SUa2wRmiCFU6HEgyNgnGI/078O+A27eXCA=="/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.15</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:04:34 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>202602150</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.15</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.15</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Discord: unlock rich interactive agent prompts with Components v2 (buttons, selects, modals, and attachment-backed file blocks) so for native interaction through Discord. Thanks @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Discord: components v2 UI + embeds passthrough + exec approval UX refinements (CV2 containers, button layout, Discord-forwarding skip). Thanks @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
<li>Plugins: expose <code>llm_input</code> and <code>llm_output</code> hook payloads so extensions can observe prompt/input context and model output usage details. (#16724) Thanks @SecondThread.</li>
<li>Subagents: nested sub-agents (sub-sub-agents) with configurable depth. Set <code>agents.defaults.subagents.maxSpawnDepth: 2</code> to allow sub-agents to spawn their own children. Includes <code>maxChildrenPerAgent</code> limit (default 5), depth-aware tool policy, and proper announce chain routing. (#14447) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Slack/Discord/Telegram: add per-channel ack reaction overrides (account/channel-level) to support platform-specific emoji formats. (#17092) Thanks @zerone0x.</li>
<li>Cron/Gateway: add finished-run webhook delivery toggle (<code>notify</code>) and dedicated webhook auth token support (<code>cron.webhookToken</code>) for outbound cron webhook posts. (#14535) Thanks @advaitpaliwal.</li>
<li>Channels: deduplicate probe/token resolution base types across core + extensions while preserving per-channel error typing. (#16986) Thanks @iyoda and @thewilloftheshadow.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Security: replace deprecated SHA-1 sandbox configuration hashing with SHA-256 for deterministic sandbox cache identity and recreation checks. Thanks @kexinoh.</li>
<li>Security/Logging: redact Telegram bot tokens from error messages and uncaught stack traces to prevent accidental secret leakage into logs. Thanks @aether-ai-agent.</li>
<li>Sandbox/Security: block dangerous sandbox Docker config (bind mounts, host networking, unconfined seccomp/apparmor) to prevent container escape via config injection. Thanks @aether-ai-agent.</li>
<li>Sandbox: preserve array order in config hashing so order-sensitive Docker/browser settings trigger container recreation correctly. Thanks @kexinoh.</li>
<li>Gateway/Security: redact sensitive session/path details from <code>status</code> responses for non-admin clients; full details remain available to <code>operator.admin</code>. (#8590) Thanks @fr33d3m0n.</li>
<li>Gateway/Control UI: preserve requested operator scopes for Control UI bypass modes (<code>allowInsecureAuth</code> / <code>dangerouslyDisableDeviceAuth</code>) when device identity is unavailable, preventing false <code>missing scope</code> failures on authenticated LAN/HTTP operator sessions. (#17682) Thanks @leafbird.</li>
<li>LINE/Security: fail closed on webhook startup when channel token or channel secret is missing, and treat LINE accounts as configured only when both are present. (#17587) Thanks @davidahmann.</li>
<li>Skills/Security: restrict <code>download</code> installer <code>targetDir</code> to the per-skill tools directory to prevent arbitrary file writes. Thanks @Adam55A-code.</li>
<li>Skills/Linux: harden go installer fallback on apt-based systems by handling root/no-sudo environments safely, doing best-effort apt index refresh, and returning actionable errors instead of failing with spawn errors. (#17687) Thanks @mcrolly.</li>
<li>Web Fetch/Security: cap downloaded response body size before HTML parsing to prevent memory exhaustion from oversized or deeply nested pages. Thanks @xuemian168.</li>
<li>Config/Gateway: make sensitive-key whitelist suffix matching case-insensitive while preserving <code>passwordFile</code> path exemptions, preventing accidental redaction of non-secret config values like <code>maxTokens</code> and IRC password-file paths. (#16042) Thanks @akramcodez.</li>
<li>Dev tooling: harden git <code>pre-commit</code> hook against option injection from malicious filenames (for example <code>--force</code>), preventing accidental staging of ignored files. Thanks @mrthankyou.</li>
<li>Gateway/Agent: reject malformed <code>agent:</code>-prefixed session keys (for example, <code>agent:main</code>) in <code>agent</code> and <code>agent.identity.get</code> instead of silently resolving them to the default agent, preventing accidental cross-session routing. (#15707) Thanks @rodrigouroz.</li>
<li>Gateway/Chat: harden <code>chat.send</code> inbound message handling by rejecting null bytes, stripping unsafe control characters, and normalizing Unicode to NFC before dispatch. (#8593) Thanks @fr33d3m0n.</li>
<li>Gateway/Send: return an actionable error when <code>send</code> targets internal-only <code>webchat</code>, guiding callers to use <code>chat.send</code> or a deliverable channel. (#15703) Thanks @rodrigouroz.</li>
<li>Control UI: prevent stored XSS via assistant name/avatar by removing inline script injection, serving bootstrap config as JSON, and enforcing <code>script-src 'self'</code>. Thanks @Adam55A-code.</li>
<li>Agents/Security: sanitize workspace paths before embedding into LLM prompts (strip Unicode control/format chars) to prevent instruction injection via malicious directory names. Thanks @aether-ai-agent.</li>
<li>Agents/Sandbox: clarify system prompt path guidance so sandbox <code>bash/exec</code> uses container paths (for example <code>/workspace</code>) while file tools keep host-bridge mapping, avoiding first-attempt path misses from host-only absolute paths in sandbox command execution. (#17693) Thanks @app/juniordevbot.</li>
<li>Agents/Context: apply configured model <code>contextWindow</code> overrides after provider discovery so <code>lookupContextTokens()</code> honors operator config values (including discovery-failure paths). (#17404) Thanks @michaelbship and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Agents/Context: derive <code>lookupContextTokens()</code> from auth-available model metadata and keep the smallest discovered context window for duplicate model ids, preventing cross-provider cache collisions from overestimating session context limits. (#17586) Thanks @githabideri and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Agents/OpenAI: force <code>store=true</code> for direct OpenAI Responses/Codex runs to preserve multi-turn server-side conversation state, while leaving proxy/non-OpenAI endpoints unchanged. (#16803) Thanks @mark9232 and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Memory/FTS: make <code>buildFtsQuery</code> Unicode-aware so non-ASCII queries (including CJK) produce keyword tokens instead of falling back to vector-only search. (#17672) Thanks @KinGP5471.</li>
<li>Auto-reply/Compaction: resolve <code>memory/YYYY-MM-DD.md</code> placeholders with timezone-aware runtime dates and append a <code>Current time:</code> line to memory-flush turns, preventing wrong-year memory filenames without making the system prompt time-variant. (#17603, #17633) Thanks @nicholaspapadam-wq and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Agents: return an explicit timeout error reply when an embedded run times out before producing any payloads, preventing silent dropped turns during slow cache-refresh transitions. (#16659) Thanks @liaosvcaf and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>Group chats: always inject group chat context (name, participants, reply guidance) into the system prompt on every turn, not just the first. Prevents the model from losing awareness of which group it's in and incorrectly using the message tool to send to the same group. (#14447) Thanks @tyler6204.</li>
<li>Browser/Agents: when browser control service is unavailable, return explicit non-retry guidance (instead of "try again") so models do not loop on repeated browser tool calls until timeout. (#17673) Thanks @austenstone.</li>
<li>Subagents: use child-run-based deterministic announce idempotency keys across direct and queued delivery paths (with legacy queued-item fallback) to prevent duplicate announce retries without collapsing distinct same-millisecond announces. (#17150) Thanks @widingmarcus-cyber.</li>
<li>Subagents/Models: preserve <code>agents.defaults.model.fallbacks</code> when subagent sessions carry a model override, so subagent runs fail over to configured fallback models instead of retrying only the overridden primary model.</li>
<li>Telegram: omit <code>message_thread_id</code> for DM sends/draft previews and keep forum-topic handling (<code>id=1</code> general omitted, non-general kept), preventing DM failures with <code>400 Bad Request: message thread not found</code>. (#10942) Thanks @garnetlyx.</li>
<li>Telegram: replace inbound <code><media:audio></code> placeholder with successful preflight voice transcript in message body context, preventing placeholder-only prompt bodies for mention-gated voice messages. (#16789) Thanks @Limitless2023.</li>
<li>Telegram: retry inbound media <code>getFile</code> calls (3 attempts with backoff) and gracefully fall back to placeholder-only processing when retries fail, preventing dropped voice/media messages on transient Telegram network errors. (#16154) Thanks @yinghaosang.</li>
<li>Telegram: finalize streaming preview replies in place instead of sending a second final message, preventing duplicate Telegram assistant outputs at stream completion. (#17218) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Discord: preserve channel session continuity when runtime payloads omit <code>message.channelId</code> by falling back to event/raw <code>channel_id</code> values for routing/session keys, so same-channel messages keep history across turns/restarts. Also align diagnostics so active Discord runs no longer appear as <code>sessionKey=unknown</code>. (#17622) Thanks @shakkernerd.</li>
<li>Discord: dedupe native skill commands by skill name in multi-agent setups to prevent duplicated slash commands with <code>_2</code> suffixes. (#17365) Thanks @seewhyme.</li>
<li>Discord: ensure role allowlist matching uses raw role IDs for message routing authorization. Thanks @xinhuagu.</li>
<li>Web UI/Agents: hide <code>BOOTSTRAP.md</code> in the Agents Files list after onboarding is completed, avoiding confusing missing-file warnings for completed workspaces. (#17491) Thanks @gumadeiras.</li>
<li>Auto-reply/WhatsApp/TUI/Web: when a final assistant message is <code>NO_REPLY</code> and a messaging tool send succeeded, mirror the delivered messaging-tool text into session-visible assistant output so TUI/Web no longer show <code>NO_REPLY</code> placeholders. (#7010) Thanks @Morrowind-Xie.</li>
<li>Cron: infer <code>payload.kind="agentTurn"</code> for model-only <code>cron.update</code> payload patches, so partial agent-turn updates do not fail validation when <code>kind</code> is omitted. (#15664) Thanks @rodrigouroz.</li>
<li>TUI: make searchable-select filtering and highlight rendering ANSI-aware so queries ignore hidden escape codes and no longer corrupt ANSI styling sequences during match highlighting. (#4519) Thanks @bee4come.</li>
<li>TUI/Windows: coalesce rapid single-line submit bursts in Git Bash into one multiline message as a fallback when bracketed paste is unavailable, preventing pasted multiline text from being split into multiple sends. (#4986) Thanks @adamkane.</li>
<li>TUI: suppress false <code>(no output)</code> placeholders for non-local empty final events during concurrent runs, preventing external-channel replies from showing empty assistant bubbles while a local run is still streaming. (#5782) Thanks @LagWizard and @vignesh07.</li>
<li>TUI: preserve copy-sensitive long tokens (URLs/paths/file-like identifiers) during wrapping and overflow sanitization so wrapped output no longer inserts spaces that corrupt copy/paste values. (#17515, #17466, #17505) Thanks @abe238, @trevorpan, and @JasonCry.</li>
<li>CLI/Build: make legacy daemon CLI compatibility shim generation tolerant of minimal tsdown daemon export sets, while preserving restart/register compatibility aliases and surfacing explicit errors for unavailable legacy daemon commands. Thanks @vignesh07.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.15/OpenClaw-2026.2.15.zip" length="22896513" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="MLGsd2NeHXFRH1Or0bFQnAjqfuuJDuhl1mvKFIqTQcRvwbeyvOyyLXrqSbmaOgJR3wBQBKLs6jYQ9dQ/3R8RCg=="/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026.2.26</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 23:37:15 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openclaw/openclaw/main/appcast.xml</link>
            <sparkle:version>202602260</sparkle:version>
            <sparkle:shortVersionString>2026.2.26</sparkle:shortVersionString>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>15.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>OpenClaw 2026.2.26</h2>
<h3>Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Highlight: External Secrets Management introduces a full <code>openclaw secrets</code> workflow (<code>audit</code>, <code>configure</code>, <code>apply</code>, <code>reload</code>) with runtime snapshot activation, strict <code>secrets apply</code> target-path validation, safer migration scrubbing, ref-only auth-profile support, and dedicated docs. (#26155) Thanks @joshavant.</li>
<li>ACP/Thread-bound agents: make ACP agents first-class runtimes for thread sessions with <code>acp</code> spawn/send dispatch integration, acpx backend bridging, lifecycle controls, startup reconciliation, runtime cleanup, and coalesced thread replies. (#23580) thanks @osolmaz.</li>
<li>Agents/Routing CLI: add <code>openclaw agents bindings</code>, <code>openclaw agents bind</code>, and <code>openclaw agents unbind</code> for account-scoped route management, including channel-only to account-scoped binding upgrades, role-aware binding identity handling, plugin-resolved binding account IDs, and optional account-binding prompts in <code>openclaw channels add</code>. (#27195) thanks @gumadeiras.</li>
<li>Codex/WebSocket transport: make <code>openai-codex</code> WebSocket-first by default (<code>transport: "auto"</code> with SSE fallback), keep explicit per-model/runtime transport overrides, and add regression coverage + docs for transport selection.</li>
<li>Onboarding/Plugins: let channel plugins own interactive onboarding flows with optional <code>configureInteractive</code> and <code>configureWhenConfigured</code> hooks while preserving the generic fallback path. (#27191) thanks @gumadeiras.</li>
<li>Android/Nodes: add Android <code>device</code> capability plus <code>device.status</code> and <code>device.info</code> node commands, including runtime handler wiring and protocol/registry coverage for device status/info payloads. (#27664) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Android/Nodes: add <code>notifications.list</code> support on Android nodes and expose <code>nodes notifications_list</code> in agent tooling for listing active device notifications. (#27344) thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Docs/Contributing: add Nimrod Gutman to the maintainer roster in <code>CONTRIBUTING.md</code>. (#27840) Thanks @ngutman.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Telegram/DM allowlist runtime inheritance: enforce <code>dmPolicy: "allowlist"</code> <code>allowFrom</code> requirements using effective account-plus-parent config across account-capable channels (Telegram, Discord, Slack, Signal, iMessage, IRC, BlueBubbles, WhatsApp), and align <code>openclaw doctor</code> checks to the same inheritance logic so DM traffic is not silently dropped after upgrades. (#27936) Thanks @widingmarcus-cyber.</li>
<li>Delivery queue/recovery backoff: prevent retry starvation by persisting <code>lastAttemptAt</code> on failed sends and deferring recovery retries until each entry's <code>lastAttemptAt + backoff</code> window is eligible, while continuing to recover ready entries behind deferred ones. Landed from contributor PR #27710 by @Jimmy-xuzimo. Thanks @Jimmy-xuzimo.</li>
<li>Google Chat/Lifecycle: keep Google Chat <code>startAccount</code> pending until abort in webhook mode so startup is no longer interpreted as immediate exit, preventing auto-restart loops and webhook-target churn. (#27384) thanks @junsuwhy.</li>
<li>Temp dirs/Linux umask: force <code>0700</code> permissions after temp-dir creation and self-heal existing writable temp dirs before trust checks so <code>umask 0002</code> installs no longer crash-loop on startup. Landed from contributor PR #27860 by @stakeswky. (#27853) Thanks @stakeswky.</li>
<li>Nextcloud Talk/Lifecycle: keep <code>startAccount</code> pending until abort and stop the webhook monitor on shutdown, preventing <code>EADDRINUSE</code> restart loops when the gateway manages account lifecycle. (#27897)</li>
<li>Microsoft Teams/File uploads: acknowledge <code>fileConsent/invoke</code> immediately (<code>invokeResponse</code> before upload + file card send) so Teams no longer shows false "Something went wrong" timeout banners while upload completion continues asynchronously; includes updated async regression coverage. Landed from contributor PR #27641 by @scz2011.</li>
<li>Queue/Drain/Cron reliability: harden lane draining with guaranteed <code>draining</code> flag reset on synchronous pump failures, reject new queue enqueues during gateway restart drain windows (instead of silently killing accepted tasks), add <code>/stop</code> queued-backlog cutoff metadata with stale-message skipping (while avoiding cross-session native-stop cutoff bleed), and raise isolated cron <code>agentTurn</code> outer safety timeout to avoid false 10-minute timeout races against longer agent session timeouts. (#27407, #27332, #27427)</li>
<li>Typing/Main reply pipeline: always mark dispatch idle in <code>agent-runner</code> finalization so typing cleanup runs even when dispatcher <code>onIdle</code> does not fire, preventing stuck typing indicators after run completion. (#27250) Thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Typing/TTL safety net: add max-duration guardrails to shared typing callbacks so stuck lifecycle edges auto-stop typing indicators even when explicit idle/cleanup signals are missed. (#27428) Thanks @Crpdim.</li>
<li>Typing/Cross-channel leakage: unify run-scoped typing suppression for cross-channel/internal-webchat routes, preserve current inbound origin as embedded run message channel context, harden shared typing keepalive with consecutive-failure circuit breaker edge-case handling, and enforce dispatcher completion/idle waits in extension dispatcher callsites (Feishu, Matrix, Mattermost, MSTeams) so typing indicators always clean up on success/error paths. Related: #27647, #27493, #27598. Supersedes/replaces draft PRs: #27640, #27593, #27540.</li>
<li>Telegram/sendChatAction 401 handling: add bounded exponential backoff + temporary local typing suppression after repeated unauthorized failures to stop unbounded <code>sendChatAction</code> retry loops that can trigger Telegram abuse enforcement and bot deletion. (#27415) Thanks @widingmarcus-cyber.</li>
<li>Telegram/Webhook startup: clarify webhook config guidance, allow <code>channels.telegram.webhookPort: 0</code> for ephemeral listener binding, and log both the local listener URL and Telegram-advertised webhook URL with the bound port. (#25732) thanks @huntharo.</li>
<li>Browser/Chrome extension handshake: bind relay WS message handling before <code>onopen</code> and add non-blocking <code>connect.challenge</code> response handling for gateway-style handshake frames, avoiding stuck <code></code> badge states when challenge frames arrive immediately on connect. Landed from contributor PR #22571 by @pandego. (#22553)</li>
<li>Browser/Extension relay init: dedupe concurrent same-port relay startup with shared in-flight initialization promises so callers await one startup lifecycle and receive consistent success/failure results. Landed from contributor PR #21277 by @HOYALIM. (Related #20688)</li>
<li>Browser/Fill relay + CLI parity: accept <code>act.fill</code> fields without explicit <code>type</code> by defaulting missing/empty <code>type</code> to <code>text</code> in both browser relay route parsing and <code>openclaw browser fill</code> CLI field parsing, so relay calls no longer fail when the model omits field type metadata. Landed from contributor PR #27662 by @Uface11. (#27296) Thanks @Uface11.</li>
<li>Feishu/Permission error dispatch: merge sender-name permission notices into the main inbound dispatch so one user message produces one agent turn/reply (instead of a duplicate permission-notice turn), with regression coverage. (#27381) thanks @byungsker.</li>
<li>Agents/Canvas default node resolution: when multiple connected canvas-capable nodes exist and no single <code>mac-*</code> candidate is selected, default to the first connected candidate instead of failing with <code>node required</code> for implicit-node canvas tool calls. Landed from contributor PR #27444 by @carbaj03. Thanks @carbaj03.</li>
<li>TUI/stream assembly: preserve streamed text across real tool-boundary drops without keeping stale streamed text when non-text blocks appear only in the final payload. Landed from contributor PR #27711 by @scz2011. (#27674)</li>
<li>Hooks/Internal <code>message:sent</code>: forward <code>sessionKey</code> on outbound sends from agent delivery, cron isolated delivery, gateway receipt acks, heartbeat sends, session-maintenance warnings, and restart-sentinel recovery so internal <code>message:sent</code> hooks consistently dispatch with session context, including <code>openclaw agent --deliver</code> runs resumed via <code>--session-id</code> (without explicit <code>--session-key</code>). Landed from contributor PR #27584 by @qualiobra. Thanks @qualiobra.</li>
<li>Pi image-token usage: stop re-injecting history image blocks each turn, process image references from the current prompt only, and prune already-answered user-image blocks in stored history to prevent runaway token growth. (#27602)</li>
<li>BlueBubbles/SSRF: auto-allowlist the configured <code>serverUrl</code> hostname for attachment fetches so localhost/private-IP BlueBubbles setups are no longer false-blocked by default SSRF checks. Landed from contributor PR #27648 by @lailoo. (#27599) Thanks @taylorhou for reporting.</li>
<li>Agents/Compaction + onboarding safety: prevent destructive double-compaction by stripping stale assistant usage around compaction boundaries, skipping post-compaction custom metadata writes in the same attempt, and cancelling safeguard compaction when there are no real conversation messages to summarize; harden workspace/bootstrap detection for memory-backed workspaces; and change <code>openclaw onboard --reset</code> default scope to <code>config+creds+sessions</code> (workspace deletion now requires <code>--reset-scope full</code>). (#26458, #27314) Thanks @jaden-clovervnd, @Sid-Qin, and @widingmarcus-cyber for fix direction in #26502, #26529, and #27492.</li>
<li>NO_REPLY suppression: suppress <code>NO_REPLY</code> before Slack API send and in sub-agent announce completion flow so sentinel text no longer leaks into user channels. Landed from contributor PRs #27529 (by @Sid-Qin) and #27535 (rewritten minimal landing by maintainers). (#27387, #27531)</li>
<li>Matrix/Group sender identity: preserve sender labels in Matrix group inbound prompt text (<code>BodyForAgent</code>) for both channel and threaded messages, and align group envelopes with shared inbound sender-prefix formatting so first-person requests resolve against the current sender. (#27401) thanks @koushikxd.</li>
<li>Auto-reply/Streaming: suppress only exact <code>NO_REPLY</code> final replies while still filtering streaming partial sentinel fragments (<code>NO_</code>, <code>NO_RE</code>, <code>HEARTBEAT_...</code>) so substantive replies ending with <code>NO_REPLY</code> are delivered and partial silent tokens do not leak during streaming. (#19576) Thanks @aldoeliacim.</li>
<li>Auto-reply/Inbound metadata: add a readable <code>timestamp</code> field to conversation info and ignore invalid/out-of-range timestamp values so prompt assembly never crashes on malformed timestamp inputs. (#17017) thanks @liuy.</li>
<li>Typing/Run completion race: prevent post-run keepalive ticks from re-triggering typing callbacks by guarding <code>triggerTyping()</code> with <code>runComplete</code>, with regression coverage for no-restart behavior during run-complete/dispatch-idle boundaries. (#27413) Thanks @widingmarcus-cyber.</li>
<li>Typing/Dispatch idle: force typing cleanup when <code>markDispatchIdle</code> never arrives after run completion, avoiding leaked typing keepalive loops in cron/announce edges. Landed from contributor PR #27541 by @Sid-Qin. (#27493)</li>
<li>Telegram/Inline buttons: allow callback-query button handling in groups (including <code>/models</code> follow-up buttons) when group policy authorizes the sender, by removing the redundant callback allowlist gate that blocked open-policy groups. (#27343) Thanks @GodsBoy.</li>
<li>Telegram/Streaming preview: when finalizing without an existing preview message, prime pending preview text with final answer before stop-flush so users do not briefly see stale 1-2 word fragments (for example <code>no</code> before <code>no problem</code>). (#27449) Thanks @emanuelst for the original fix direction in #19673.</li>
<li>Browser/Extension relay CORS: handle <code>/json*</code> <code>OPTIONS</code> preflight before auth checks, allow Chrome extension origins, and return extension-origin CORS headers on relay HTTP responses so extension token validation no longer fails cross-origin. Landed from contributor PR #23962 by @miloudbelarebia. (#23842)</li>
<li>Browser/Extension relay auth: allow <code>?token=</code> query-param auth on relay <code>/json*</code> endpoints (consistent with relay WebSocket auth) so curl/devtools-style <code>/json/version</code> and <code>/json/list</code> probes work without requiring custom headers. Landed from contributor PR #26015 by @Sid-Qin. (#25928)</li>
<li>Browser/Extension relay shutdown: flush pending extension-request timers/rejections during relay <code>stop()</code> before socket/server teardown so in-flight extension waits do not survive shutdown windows. Landed from contributor PR #24142 by @kevinWangSheng.</li>
<li>Browser/Extension relay reconnect resilience: keep CDP clients alive across brief MV3 extension disconnect windows, wait briefly for extension reconnect before failing in-flight CDP commands, and only tear down relay target/client state after reconnect grace expires. Landed from contributor PR #27617 by @davidemanuelDEV.</li>
<li>Browser/Route decode hardening: guard malformed percent-encoding in relay target action routes and browser route-param decoding so crafted <code>%</code> paths return <code>400</code> instead of crashing/unhandled URI decode failures. Landed from contributor PR #11880 by @Yida-Dev.</li>
<li>Feishu/Inbound message metadata: include inbound <code>message_id</code> in <code>BodyForAgent</code> on a dedicated metadata line so agents can reliably correlate and act on media/message operations that require message IDs, with regression coverage. (#27253) thanks @xss925175263.</li>
<li>Feishu/Doc tools: route <code>feishu_doc</code> and <code>feishu_app_scopes</code> through the active agent account context (with explicit <code>accountId</code> override support) so multi-account agents no longer default to the first configured app, with regression coverage for context routing and explicit override behavior. (#27338) thanks @AaronL725.</li>
<li>LINE/Inline directives auth: gate directive parsing (<code>/model</code>, <code>/think</code>, <code>/verbose</code>, <code>/reasoning</code>, <code>/queue</code>) on resolved authorization (<code>command.isAuthorizedSender</code>) so <code>commands.allowFrom</code>-authorized LINE senders are not silently stripped when raw <code>CommandAuthorized</code> is unset. Landed from contributor PR #27248 by @kevinWangSheng. (#27240)</li>
<li>Onboarding/Gateway: seed default Control UI <code>allowedOrigins</code> for non-loopback binds during onboarding (<code>localhost</code>/<code>127.0.0.1</code> plus custom bind host) so fresh non-loopback setups do not fail startup due to missing origin policy. (#26157) thanks @stakeswky.</li>
<li>Docker/GCP onboarding: reduce first-build OOM risk by capping Node heap during <code>pnpm install</code>, reuse existing gateway token during <code>docker-setup.sh</code> reruns so <code>.env</code> stays aligned with config, auto-bootstrap Control UI allowed origins for non-loopback Docker binds, and add GCP docs guidance for tokenized dashboard links + pairing recovery commands. (#26253) Thanks @pandego.</li>
<li>CLI/Gateway <code>--force</code> in non-root Docker: recover from <code>lsof</code> permission failures (<code>EACCES</code>/<code>EPERM</code>) by falling back to <code>fuser</code> kill + probe-based port checks, so <code>openclaw gateway --force</code> works for default container <code>node</code> user flows. (#27941)</li>
<li>Gateway/Bind visibility: emit a startup warning when binding to non-loopback addresses so operators get explicit exposure guidance in runtime logs. (#25397) thanks @let5sne.</li>
<li>Sessions cleanup/Doctor: add <code>openclaw sessions cleanup --fix-missing</code> to prune store entries whose transcript files are missing, including doctor guidance and CLI coverage. Landed from contributor PR #27508 by @Sid-Qin. (#27422)</li>
<li>Doctor/State integrity: ignore metadata-only slash routing sessions when checking recent missing transcripts so <code>openclaw doctor</code> no longer reports false-positive transcript-missing warnings for <code>*:slash:*</code> keys. (#27375) thanks @gumadeiras.</li>
<li>CLI/Gateway status: force local <code>gateway status</code> probe host to <code>127.0.0.1</code> for <code>bind=lan</code> so co-located probes do not trip non-loopback plaintext WebSocket checks. (#26997) thanks @chikko80.</li>
<li>CLI/Gateway auth: align <code>gateway run --auth</code> parsing/help text with supported gateway auth modes by accepting <code>none</code> and <code>trusted-proxy</code> (in addition to <code>token</code>/<code>password</code>) for CLI overrides. (#27469) thanks @s1korrrr.</li>
<li>CLI/Daemon status TLS probe: use <code>wss://</code> and forward local TLS certificate fingerprint for TLS-enabled gateway daemon probes so <code>openclaw daemon status</code> works with <code>gateway.bind=lan</code> + <code>gateway.tls.enabled=true</code>. (#24234) thanks @liuy.</li>
<li>Podman/Default bind: change <code>run-openclaw-podman.sh</code> default gateway bind from <code>lan</code> to <code>loopback</code> and document explicit LAN opt-in with Control UI origin configuration. (#27491) thanks @robbyczgw-cla.</li>
<li>Daemon/macOS launchd: forward proxy env vars into supervised service environments, keep LaunchAgent <code>KeepAlive=true</code> semantics, and harden restart sequencing to <code>print -> bootout -> wait old pid exit -> bootstrap -> kickstart</code>. (#27276) thanks @frankekn.</li>
<li>Gateway/macOS restart-loop hardening: detect OpenClaw-managed supervisor markers during SIGUSR1 restart handoff, clean stale gateway PIDs before <code>/restart</code> launchctl/systemctl triggers, and set LaunchAgent <code>ThrottleInterval=60</code> to bound launchd retry storms during lock-release races. Landed from contributor PRs #27655 (@taw0002), #27448 (@Sid-Qin), and #27650 (@kevinWangSheng). (#27605, #27590, #26904, #26736)</li>
<li>Models/MiniMax auth header defaults: set <code>authHeader: true</code> for both onboarding-generated MiniMax API providers and implicit built-in MiniMax (<code>minimax</code>, <code>minimax-portal</code>) provider templates so first requests no longer fail with MiniMax <code>401 authentication_error</code> due to missing <code>Authorization</code> header. Landed from contributor PRs #27622 by @riccoyuanft and #27631 by @kevinWangSheng. (#27600, #15303)</li>
<li>Auth/Auth profiles: normalize <code>auth-profiles.json</code> alias fields (<code>mode -> type</code>, <code>apiKey -> key</code>) before credential validation so entries copied from <code>openclaw.json</code> auth examples are no longer silently dropped. (#26950) thanks @byungsker.</li>
<li>Models/Profile suffix parsing: centralize trailing <code>@profile</code> parsing and only treat <code>@</code> as a profile separator when it appears after the final <code>/</code>, preserving model IDs like <code>openai/@cf/...</code> and <code>openrouter/@preset/...</code> across <code>/model</code> directive parsing and allowlist model resolution, with regression coverage.</li>
<li>Models/OpenAI Codex config schema parity: accept <code>openai-codex-responses</code> in the config model API schema and TypeScript <code>ModelApi</code> union, with regression coverage for config validation. Landed from contributor PR #27501 by @AytuncYildizli. Thanks @AytuncYildizli.</li>
<li>Agents/Models config: preserve agent-level provider <code>apiKey</code> and <code>baseUrl</code> during merge-mode <code>models.json</code> updates when agent values are present. (#27293) thanks @Sid-Qin.</li>
<li>Azure OpenAI Responses: force <code>store=true</code> for <code>azure-openai-responses</code> direct responses API calls to avoid multi-turn 400 failures. Landed from contributor PR #27499 by @polarbear-Yang. (#27497)</li>
<li>Security/Node exec approvals: require structured <code>commandArgv</code> approvals for <code>host=node</code>, enforce versioned <code>systemRunBindingV1</code> matching for argv/cwd/session/agent/env context with fail-closed behavior on missing/mismatched bindings, and add <code>GIT_EXTERNAL_DIFF</code> to blocked host env keys. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.26</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Plugin channel HTTP auth: normalize protected <code>/api/channels</code> path checks against canonicalized request paths (case + percent-decoding + slash normalization), resolve encoded dot-segment traversal variants, and fail closed on malformed <code>%</code>-encoded channel prefixes so alternate-path variants cannot bypass gateway auth. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.26</code>). Thanks @zpbrent for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Gateway node pairing: pin paired-device <code>platform</code>/<code>deviceFamily</code> metadata across reconnects and bind those fields into device-auth signatures, so reconnect metadata spoofing cannot expand node command allowlists without explicit repair pairing. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.26</code>). Thanks @76embiid21 for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Sandbox path alias guard: reject broken symlink targets by resolving through existing ancestors and failing closed on out-of-root targets, preventing workspace-only <code>apply_patch</code> writes from escaping sandbox/workspace boundaries via dangling symlinks. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.26</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Workspace FS boundary aliases: harden canonical boundary resolution for non-existent-leaf symlink aliases while preserving valid in-root aliases, preventing first-write workspace escapes via out-of-root symlink targets. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.26</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Config includes: harden <code>$include</code> file loading with verified-open reads, reject hardlinked include aliases, and enforce include file-size guardrails so config include resolution remains bounded to trusted in-root files. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.26</code>). Thanks @zpbrent for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Node exec approvals hardening: freeze immutable approval-time execution plans (<code>argv</code>/<code>cwd</code>/<code>agentId</code>/<code>sessionKey</code>) via <code>system.run.prepare</code>, enforce those canonical plan values during approval forwarding/execution, and reject mutable parent-symlink cwd paths during approval-plan building to prevent approval bypass via symlink rebind. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.26</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Microsoft Teams media fetch: route Graph message/hosted-content/attachment fetches and auth-scope fallback attachment downloads through shared SSRF-guarded fetch paths, and centralize hostname-suffix allowlist policy helpers in the plugin SDK to remove channel/plugin drift. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.26</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Voice Call (Twilio): bind webhook replay + manager dedupe identity to authenticated request material, remove unsigned <code>i-twilio-idempotency-token</code> trust from replay/dedupe keys, and thread verified request identity through provider parse flow to harden cross-provider event dedupe. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.26</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting.</li>
<li>Security/Exec approvals forwarding: prefer turn-source channel/account/thread metadata when resolving approval delivery targets so stale session routes do not misroute approval prompts.</li>
<li>Security/Pairing multi-account isolation: enforce account-scoped pairing allowlists and pending-request storage across core + extension message channels while preserving channel-scoped defaults for the default account. This ships in the next npm release (<code>2026.2.26</code>). Thanks @tdjackey for reporting and @gumadeiras for implementation.</li>
<li>Config/Plugins entries: treat unknown <code>plugins.entries.*</code> ids as startup warnings (ignored stale keys) instead of hard validation failures that can crash-loop gateway boot. Landed from contributor PR #27506 by @Sid-Qin. (#27455)</li>
<li>Telegram native commands: degrade command registration on <code>BOT_COMMANDS_TOO_MUCH</code> by retrying with fewer commands instead of crash-looping startup sync. Landed from contributor PR #27512 by @Sid-Qin. (#27456)</li>
<li>Web tools/Proxy: route <code>web_search</code> provider HTTP calls (Brave, Perplexity, xAI, Gemini, Kimi), redirect resolution, and <code>web_fetch</code> through a shared proxy-aware SSRF guard path so gateway installs behind <code>HTTP_PROXY</code>/<code>HTTPS_PROXY</code>/<code>ALL_PROXY</code> no longer fail with transport <code>fetch failed</code> errors. (#27430) thanks @kevinWangSheng.</li>
<li>Android/Node invoke: remove native gateway WebSocket <code>Origin</code> header to avoid false origin rejections, unify invoke command registry/policy/error parsing paths, and keep command availability checks centralized to reduce dispatcher/advertisement drift. (#27257) Thanks @obviyus.</li>
<li>Gateway shared-auth scopes: preserve requested operator scopes for shared-token clients when device identity is unavailable, instead of clearing scopes during auth handling. Landed from contributor PR #27498 by @kevinWangSheng. (#27494)</li>
<li>Cron/Hooks isolated routing: preserve canonical <code>agent:*</code> session keys in isolated runs so already-qualified keys are not double-prefixed (for example <code>agent:main:main</code> no longer becomes <code>agent:main:agent:main:main</code>). Landed from contributor PR #27333 by @MaheshBhushan. (#27289, #27282)</li>
<li>Channels/Multi-account config: when adding a non-default channel account to a single-account top-level channel setup, move existing account-scoped top-level single-account values into <code>channels.<channel>.accounts.default</code> before writing the new account so the original account keeps working without duplicated account values at channel root; <code>openclaw doctor --fix</code> now repairs previously mixed channel account shapes the same way. (#27334) thanks @gumadeiras.</li>
<li>iOS/Talk mode: stop injecting the voice directive hint into iOS Talk prompts and remove the Voice Directive Hint setting, reducing model bias toward tool-style TTS directives and keeping relay responses text-first by default. (#27543) thanks @ngutman.</li>
<li>CI/Windows: shard the Windows <code>checks-windows</code> test lane into two matrix jobs and honor explicit shard index overrides in <code>scripts/test-parallel.mjs</code> to reduce CI critical-path wall time. (#27234) Thanks @joshavant.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">View full changelog</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/releases/download/v2026.2.26/OpenClaw-2026.2.26.zip" length="12796628" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:edSignature="qqVJfkQS9Q4LCTlGtOyXzORWZWWnOkWyiJ6DVX27oPF8aeUlUyfHrmb51sFiNjSuCJC2xmJW1Mi1CAHl/I1pCw=="/>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>